off we go right
hello YouTube Facebook our board meeting
I don't even know if we don't we're in
for our board meeting but it's what we
do every other week and this like your
thing is getting to me again let's be in
the middle I put a couple things on the
agenda just cuz I needed some things
okay for the YouTube channel or
brainstorm better than that I don't
really know what we're doing today but
I'm sure we always manage to fill the
hour move it forward so well figure it
out so um the two things I just was um
when we post something on YouTube I
don't know if we can do it through
stream you're it anyway
the stream art always seems to post as
entertainment on my channel but there's
like you can pick a category that it
normally posts as and I think both are
set to entertainment my channel and
together at Eckerd set to entertainment
I don't think entertainment covers it oh
so there's no profit and activism and
there's technology and then there's like
people and blogs which mine might fit
under but we're not working together
tech what do we want together and you
have to pick one just to be the main one
that the the UM that it automatically is
unless you write okay I mean nonprofit
and activism it's probably the closest
thing I think battery technology I was
like where's nonprofit technology
where's but yeah like who are our people
that we want to find it people who are
looking for nonprofit activism or people
who are looking for technology my guess
is nonprofit activism is more I think so
well I mean yeah it's it's definitely
not totally cut and dry like it's a
completely valid question yeah I think
in the short term it'll be nonprofit
activism and then when we get enough
momentum and we go more mainstream than
I'm late tech hmm alright sounds good
and then the other thing I just had on
the agenda was every other week at this
time or Duty Nydia cafes right for our
projects I have no idea what questions
for those look like so brainstorming
some questions and then you can just
make a schedule and then pick one but
that's half of why this is dead all
right
videos aren't posted before
and is like I think of them and I just
procrastinate on that into laters we can
generate three or four questions that
then you know we don't need to visit it
again for another couple weeks and then
we can write and we can rotate them it
doesn't need to be new ones every time
but and on the idea cafes that
completely open or is that meant to be
idea cafes sort of adjacent to together
tactic idea Cafe is its own YouTube
channel right that I do every Tuesday
and it was going to be a platform in a
day cafe is just an hour-long
conversation where everyone takes a turn
answering the question throughout two
five minutes without instruction and
then you have an open discussion so it's
got a bit of format to it but it's
mainly so people know what that question
is they're not feeling like it's just a
roundtable but it's got to be like a
question that people want to answer
about their project but you know what I
mean like it's right right cafe cafe
channel and you've got other spots
throughout the week that you do whatever
topics right right yeah okay yeah so it
sort of meant to be like a crossroads of
the idea cafe format on a topic that's
somewhat related to together tech is
that what we're saying are these by the
idea cafes
I believe the every yeah the every other
Friday idea cafe was to have an IT cafe
just cuz it's a way to have a
conversation that isn't the round table
we're all answered like one of them was
like how does your how could your your
project be used during the grand in it
right it's not known beforehand or how
do you how does trust impact you right
or how are you how do you see financee
allowing any of those things but those
questions I'm generating three or four
of them that are project specific
without the mean to project specific
right not how is wiki lecture I'm gonna
say who pandemic it's like how is your
project gonna miss to it yes we just
start out listening being I think we
start out initiate with just kind of the
basics like funding attracting users
which I guess might fall under marketing
building a landing page could even be
you know stuff like that so we talked in
like kind of a something like some
question around like how does the
marketing work for your profile it's
it's every its I guess it's answering
the question I kind of see it as it's a
working session for all for us to work
on things that help all the projects
either in the moment or building
something central for the project so so
yeah I think the topic could be
marketing and then the answer could be
Oh what am i doing on my project so you
can learn from that but what are the
problems on having that we can work shop
together although that may be that maybe
maybe that's closer to the to the
Saturday meeting so I'm gonna be getting
a mixed up but but I kind of think of it
be like I really think of it like okay
so let's tackle funding how do we fund
all the projects right how do we do a
group funding for together taxes the way
I see abut tell me that's wrong so yes
so that's part of the like Fridays is
more better project right Saturdays is
your project and the meta so yeah this
one's the port this is the board
meetings this is like how do we move the
meta project actually forward right the
other one is the idea cafe which it
doesn't need to be right it could be
that it's just a topic right it's its
marketing and then people can share
whatever they want to it's not a
question necessarily um and then we may
be able to even get experts on that to
come and talk about it and and help
brainstorm and we could change it I just
don't know if it's within my capacity
because then I can't be like finding
experts and I'm kind of all about her
shows up shows up and we're all experts
let's not worry about that and tell us
someone has a specific need so if we can
do it in the idea cafe format just so
that we don't have to format something
new and then we can kind of make it
wiggle around and run it like what are
you currently doing for marketing and
your project right and then you but
you're bringing your project to it even
though it is the meta project right like
it's like you're representing your
project but in the meta project of like
what could we do together
I find people don't understand that
they're part of the meta even when they
are so they're like oh that's not my
piece and they it's it's so creating it
the question arounds your project so
people come and bring their project and
then they're already part of the minute
I met a project right it's just like a
slightly different focus on Friday
versus our Saturday but very similar so
Saturday is really specifically it's a
it's it's your it's your project but
it's more like what have I done and what
I need help with over any topic and
that's fits the mastermind format and so
Friday is just an open idea Cafe about
projects with under a specific topic for
each week yeah because the idea is
around a question right you each take
turns answering the question so yeah so
a question might be how yeah how do you
mark it I think how do you market your
project how do you fund your projects
stuff like that what are something and I
don't know marketing may be too big
maybe it should be how do I find users
or how do you find users for your
project how do you find you get the word
out for your volunteers yeah or just how
do you build an audience oh yeah
and that's where like honestly marketing
is the word like even if it's a bad
connotation it's like no matter because
whatever your project is is it's like
that's marketing I'm just thinking
though there's there's two focuses one
is to like just get users of the parts
and one is to get volunteers for the
project and I think those are those
might be two different conversations but
they both I mean marketing is really the
user side but it could mean both you do
marketing yeah it's yours and to be fair
I think the term marketing can be a bit
loose I think a lot of people when they
hear marketing just think advertising
and I think that might get some wires
crossed so I agree with taking it a
layer two down and doing stuff like how
would you build your audience how would
you like that sort of a more and cluster
we're hitting a tree hitting the topics
which we think will do it having a
slightly nuanced a little different
might generate different conversations a
members name I'll have pretty watch it -
we'll look at the name but he had
mentioned that there's the cat that do
coffee meeting right now
I think we both well I missed it because
I don't get meds for my dad but I missed
it yesterday
like they scheduled it during our time
we've been doing this for several
minutes now so yeah and I mean a penis
mapping I'll figure it out or they won't
I was hoping to be part of that
conversation but it'll it'll be figured
out one way or the other or not and I
won't move forward with it yeah if it
wasn't during this time I would be on it
or if I was able to go to the one
yesterday and mapping really is a is
kind of I guess it could have multiple
projects underneath it but yeah yeah I
guess I still don't quite know what the
scope of what they mean by mapping for
me it I think of it like education but
they may be meaning another way but we
can we can discuss that later find out
okay look at me
yeah to like watch the video if they
post it in the Facebook group and see
what they mean by not being in an offer
or whatever I can't offer from that
space but wait this is always at noon on
Friday so for what since October
sometimes I want to keep brainstorming
topics that I think some I think that
works I put them in the agenda it's just
like how do we how do you market your
project how do you fund your project how
do you get people for your project
yeah are pretty are pretty common those
can be the the broader ones over the
next so that'll be six weeks right
because it's every other week and then
the Saturday one's pretty easy I'm gonna
start because I have so many videos that
I do every week and I keep doing them
like the morning of or the night of be
like oh crap and I don't have them up so
I'm gonna try on Sundays where I have
nothing plans to get just the videos up
for the next week so therefore a Friday
and Saturday one will be up to Sunday
the previous post you didn't game B I'm
creating just like a spreadsheet for
like what I'm up to every week people
can keep up to it part of which is
together check right but you the
Saturday and Friday so people can see
what's going on for the week or it can
go to that tab and see four together
tech Fridays what's happening together
Tech Saturdays what did happen what is
happening they'll know that every Sunday
that's posted so that you can go there
to get it I don't have to post it to
every individual person how do I send
this to URI
melih this your Twitter and your
messenger it's too much so happy one
place they can keep track of me didn't
track of them but that's me not together
attack so shouldn't we hit both topics
there Gimli
yeah I'm just idea cafe questions and
we're doing activism and nonprofit for
YouTube excellent okay and then this is
the board meeting so now we kind of talk
about what do we want to do to move the
meta project forward itself right yeah
good we're doing it like there's a few
people and which reminds me I did not
send this to Brad but I also I don't
know what with our board meeting
specifically whether people come or not
right like whether because it's our meta
projects you're more than welcome we're
not even aboard yet yeah I mean but at
the same time it is more focused on the
meta project um when someone comes to us
no idea what's going on it's a it's a
little much but like Shilo know like how
many things have you attended and you
know as much as we know anyway with
together tech and the matter project
kind of is so what was my point of that
one our meta project is moving forward I
mean I think our Facebook group has had
more activity some from us of course but
other people can posting as well and I
guess that is what like just hammering
it's the wrong word that hammer II know
what like what we want the Facebook
group to look like whether we want to
have one of us take on the posting or
updates like one of us takes it on we're
doing it every Wednesday and then we put
need the rest of it alright we do sister
update our own individual projects and
pretty not like what under together tech
are we doing in the game baby Facebook
how often do we want to be doing it and
who wants to take it on yeah so are you
thinking maybe for the updates maybe we
do a single post and then people put the
updates in the comments rather than like
I've been doing just a post per project
yeah which also works because there's a
not much activity right but it's more
inviting other people like does that
invite them in the same way as post even
saying hey ready for your weekly updates
post them here right and then we know
someone posts that everyone's
and post errors or or we can keep it
like that and he just poops I think it's
been a week I should update yeah I can i
I I have been doing it for the last
several weeks so next week I could just
on Thursday I already have it on my
calendar I can create a post and invite
people and then put mine in the comments
rather than what I've been doing and
doing what I do my updates for my main
Facebook page for the project but yeah
so I can just try that next week you
feel like so anything else we're doing I
mean we're doing solutions not so SH
amazing project raisings I put up as
something someone anyone coordinate in
the Facebook group right saying when
you're available ask for people no one's
yet to have done that but I feel good
with what we're doing we're Saturday as
a roundtable and we're not going back
and forth
but then if somebody want really wanted
a project raising I'm also I did want to
kind of figure out so I'd kind of
brought up the idea hey do we want to
have a discussion about replying to
people or phrasing the people things
because I've had a need for that I got a
couple topics so I guess I'm trying to
figure out what's the easiest way to
make that happen so I didn't know it
doesn't really fit in an idea cafe
because it's kind of more specific but
I'd be happy to do it on the cafe time
if you're if you're low on topics which
are probably not and then if not then
I'm just trying to think of the
logistics of scheduling and what do we
suggest people just throw up a doodle
and see when people available we're just
post with a time and see if anyone shows
up like you mean you want to do your own
project raising and you want it well I
mean I wanted to have that conversation
with this group and I guess I don't
really care win or how yeah so I guess
I'm just seeing what if everyone says
that there's a regular meeting time and
I guess actually we could do that I mean
I don't know it doesn't really fit even
in the idea cafe Friday things I think
the best thing to do is to put pick a
time that you want to do it and put it
up there because that's what we want
them to do right
is like pick a time you're available if
you have three or four times available
then by all means do a doodle poll and
then pick the one that most people will
say yes to but otherwise pick a time and
then let's see if people show up right
yeah and of which if I can I will be one
of those people like who else shows up
right to invite people to say this is
what it looks like to do your own
solution raising our generator right
okay yeah
yeah I was just trying to think of the
best way or if we had another meeting
time that we wanted to use for that
because I don't want to create a
separate meeting if we have it but it
sounds like we don't so yeah so I'll
just throw out a time for next week
Sandia is I don't want other people
using our time right like I don't want
other people being like I'm gonna do
because Friday is a bit but like
Saturday is our roundtables if we're
doing Project Racing's also then it was
kind of hard that 9 a.m. 2 a.m. thing
that's maybe that's not we want people
to do but like if they knew they could
schedule in at any point sign everyone's
home right now anyway people will
hopefully show up then they can schedule
it at their convenience to see who shows
up and that's what I want to give them
permission to do I've literally given
them permission on Facebook like typed
it up you said that but no one's done it
so it's like doing that so that we see
right with that yeah I guess my thought
is I don't know that anyone's going to
show up I mean you all said you would
participate but I'm just wondering
whether if I just throw a random date
time what's the chance that anyone's
gonna be able to make it and I'm a
pretty open the schedule but yeah that's
worth a try I just say that's why is
kind of thinking about is there a better
way to do it yeah and that is part of it
too because other people don't have this
conversation first right so that is like
a vulnerable thing to put yourself out
there and say hey I want to approach you
crazy and at noon on Wednesday and then
no one shows up it's gross think it's
like oh no no one likes me you know what
you know like it's a different whereas
well that's why I'm wondering whether if
we could somehow facilitate to make it
more likely that it would work but I
don't have any solutions you my only
suggestion would be like you said to
pick a time and then say hey if there's
someone who like different like meanie
and sorry you pick a time in your
to do this one minute that becomes like
the project raising time if there's two
or three throughout that week where it's
like if someone signs up for that we
knit like as a member of together tech I
know that solution raisings happen
Monday at 1:00 Thursdays at 3:00 and the
stuff at that and I can see but then we
need some other people to be able to
sign up and say yes I'm taking this slot
who's coming right so as a member I have
three slots that I know if I'm available
someone I could attend them and I can
see did someone sign up for that will I
attend it then as a project I can pick a
slot and then if there's two or three to
choose from then people will be more
likely to show up but also less likely
yeah it's like oh other people are there
although I'm wondering maybe mmm yeah
I'm thinking I wonder if we get just had
another time that was just kind of an
open meeting because we're not doing
project so are we still doing a project
raising alternating with the on
Saturdays I mean I'm more than happy to
do that for no no no that's like behind
right at the same time it's like party
though right okay so right now we don't
have any project raisings
regularly scheduled we just have the
Saturday might not be bad to do it there
just to do a project raising is it's
been a while since we've done one and
people might have kind of forgot what
that looks like and why it's good and
it's kind of an excuse to have one gives
you a spot to do it like it's we could
do that you know how we were gonna do a
9:00 a.m. 2:00 p.m. on Saturday we could
do that like we could have the odd time
someone wants a solution right and we
could hold the 2:00 p.m. slot for that
and and do them then the other option is
we can put out a doodle poll to the
community when are you usually available
we're looking to make one time slot for
project raisins and then also we can
maybe have it like have a sign-up sheet
with reasons for being the first sign up
and then have it be that hey if you've
participated in them or watched a few
sign up other what like so you know what
it looks like and we know you've come to
that you know even if you're just
participating in the comments you
like have it be then people know the
sign up and know to attend before they
have theirs and under stone know exactly
what that would be honest yeah thinking
through I think just right now what I'll
do is I'll post one in there for the
2:00 p.m. slot on Saturday because we're
not using that right and maybe that
should just be are kind of you know not
I mean you know kind of like there's a
time that a lot of people tend to be
available and then if if people will
start saying they can't attend and they
want to then we can do another digital
poll and so this meeting that I was
going to put up is is just talking about
responses to stuff it's not specifically
a recent score like actually the first
one is I get a lot of headhunters on on
LinkedIn and I'm like okay how do I tell
these people I'm never gonna use you
because you're spamming me well it's
interesting because I got a response
from one saying is if people get
frustrated with this but they don't
understand that with that you know I
were making living we're doing what
we're told and the that's the only way
the company can stay in business I'm
like well if you can't find a way to get
business without annoying people maybe
you shouldn't be in business but yeah so
but I just thought it'd be interesting
to phrase that because because some of
some of them this one guy anyways
I just think it'd be helpful to have
some thing thinking through stuff like
that yeah anyway so yeah I'll schedule
that we like tomorrow at 2:00 or next no
like next Saturday ok let me know if you
want me on Sunday to make up that video
as well yeah I can post it and just give
me the title so we can post Newton
stream yard I'll make you up stream your
capability oh yeah so we can get the
stream yard set up for it yeah yeah and
this is a non wiki election week great
the GPM not that I mean you know 9 a.m.
- seems like a rather large schedule for
a Saturday
well we said we're doing it to p.m. next
week oh yeah no that is a wiki lecture
one but I think one the Bentley is
attending is a little bit nice oh is
that is that yeah but you're anyway
lecture on yeah yeah right yeah that'll
be good so is there anything else with
in respect to meta project how we
actually look forward what's happening
in a draw within knack the project we
posted that in game be big projects or
okay you post it there and will be
posted in regular game be for people to
see it not yet I wanted to have some
stuff there to actually have some post
has anyone else posted anything they did
supposed to go in and add some stuff and
I didn't so maybe I'll do that while
we're talking okay yeah I think so far
it's been like me
Jubilee Bentley well forgetting the name
from New Zealand yeah yeah
and season those people ionically like
they've all got projects up signs so
going there and logging in a new stuff
and then we can also have you know
people signing up who don't have project
owners who just want to sort of see
what's going on they kick tires and
whatnot but for the most part I think
it's important for us to actually get
like at least a couple projects and
their active hosting stuff so that when
you go look at like the event list
there's events you look at healthy you
know there's not just me so that well
yeah as soon as we have some stuff I
think that'd make sense to post it in
the game deep space so that because I
mean when I put up the list of all the
videos for the week on Sunday part of it
is also probably adding it to that so
but no I think I am one of the project
list for together tech if not be
practical therefore together tech on
that if I can add that together tech
ones to the events as well as the
solution raising every week and the
other ones don't need to be on there
because they're not under an umbrella of
a project this specifically just that
like the idea Cafe is just game be then
on Friday one I mean
and there is a spot to post events that
don't have anything to do with a project
that we can build those if you want to
end up putting the you got faced up on
there probably makes sense to wait until
it's got a bit more people actually
using it and before that matters yeah
plus it'll be like 90 percent Jubilees
since of it i only attend Jubilees
medians so it feels like a hundred
percent jubilee meeting the thing is I
attend yeah that's true for me that must
be true for everyone
exactly you guys all have Jubilee your
meetings too right
she said all of them yes all right so
I'll do that this Sunday oh cool come on
and then a part of that will also be
tweaking that like some of these
subjects that we might be able to cover
for the idea cafes for the amount of
project right there's like questions
that we have right like what categories
do we want organized by these are
category that you have that we're
missing or the categories that we should
you know like merge that type of thing
so we can hear any of those unanswered
questions cuz right now it's not all
that well set up for that regards but
like it it's got spots for it I just
it's not they killed okay so I don't
even know what solution raising is under
because it's meta right it's like how we
create solutions together how we govern
together how governments what there
might end up being like a category for
meta projects or something like that
because yeah it is weird to explain
meta projecting it's like the Facebook
group you have these on Fridays and
Saturdays we're gonna do one on two p.m.
the week after this for a recalling a
project raising right we need a name for
the project comebacks comebacks and
quips answers to commonly asked
questions
okay let me know by Sunday and I'll
thank for that yeah you're calling their
project raising though right so that
it's under that umbrella well we can I
mean it's not it doesn't right it's not
right a project it's more just uh but
yeah we have half an hour we can do it
now if you want to know if the four of
us are good yeah if we're out of other
topics although I guess as far as the
product matter project I was thinking
you know there's a couple things that we
still kind of want to work on or or do
you think that we're just gonna kind of
build up the community first like do we
want to figure out how we're gonna start
how we're gonna eventually collect some
funds and pay for some development or
[Music]
what's the other thing or just determine
you know what software do we what you
know or is the matter project really
just a community which is fine yeah so I
think we do that way the time comes like
when we're because right now
theoretically one of us could like if we
wanted to put ten dollars in a month we
could just pick one of us that's not me
and you don't even give them the ten
bucks then they pay for the things cuz
we're not even incorporated nothing's
there but as soon as like someone else
comes on board that doesn't know us and
doesn't that's when it's like like when
someone else is dying to give us their
money that's the point we're like right
there's enough of us who want to be able
to generate or when we have something we
have to pay for right um yeah I guess
the Troy something we have to pay for
enough of a need because we decided that
the scheduling program really wasn't I
mean if we start using the one that you
know
made it it'd probably be good to just
compensate him a little bit just to
start the process flow yeah especially
if it costs him any if it costs him
anything to run it but if he just coded
it now don't this is I'm not discounting
Otis's work or anyone's work in any way
but like I've been doing this full-time
for four years where's my compensation
you know what I mean like it's like
we're putting in what we want to put in
and then we are gonna figure out at some
point how to compensate fairly but like
why that one and not a drill snack right
why that one and not that like what why
are we compensating this and not that
yeah it is what it was like I need money
you know that's a different it's never
gonna be it's never gonna be fair but
yeah but I think to get the ball rolling
you need to have you need to start
somewhere
so I don't think we'll like get a big
enough project and we gonna say oh this
is worth paying for let's do it
I think that you know if if we're
spending time doing this then you know
maybe we should all donate to a thing
and disburse but just to get the ball
kind of rolling cuz I don't think
there's ever gonna be something big
enough that if we don't start small that
early work yeah so there's also just
start with building the community
because I think that was sort of what
started this part of it was what do we
start with and I think if you just start
building your community or your audience
a they'll tell you and B you can ask
them so you can say like hey there's a
hundred of us now what's next and in my
mind we keep money out of it I think the
first step for money is we'll end up
paying for things that just the project
means right thing like if Jonas is to
like if there's actually hosting costs
involved then yeah that's maybe we paid
for that because we're fine with you
know we've all put in time but maybe
certain times are like okay if you put
an actual money we'll try to you know
buffer that a little bit yeah I mean
there's a lot of free hosting but it's
such low volume I mean you know I'm
paying
it's nothing for this project but even
my small sites actually most of
free but yeah I mean I guess we should
find out where there is and then I can't
imagine is there's not some host it cost
somewhere yeah and I I guess her perk
her per person like so far all the money
I've been spending a you know sort of
classified it in my head is being
underway collection luxury will string
yard an act I pay for them but mainly
for wiki elections so I'm fine with that
so I wanted to mention last Saturday I
missed our roundtable because I was
having the conversation with Matan about
common which is duo at the end of June
July but it'll be very beta and he's
gonna put me in touch with their other
of the person who's actually in charge
of putting people on the beta or
figuring that out cuz I it's like
Facebook meets Kickstarter with
governance involved so it's instead of
singing in pay Adriel starting wiki
lection and so he is a Kickstarter and
funds might in he lands it it's more
it's from what I understand it's not my
project but it's more hey let's figure
out politics we want to figure out
politics and people put money towards
that common goal and then together we do
a bit of governance on like maybe
there's a board of directors we decide
on this but anyone has put money in
could theoretically take over right
because they could say hey you know
you're doing it wrong we're so you just
conserve the campaign and then the
people who are putting the money in and
get involved can actually chipped it and
change it and so that's very exciting to
me because that's like yes it exists
that sounds really cool so it sounds
like there's a way to also get money
from that but I don't know if it'll be
within our alignment because then we'd
have to like pass it we'd have to pass
off control of the people oh wait that's
what we want so oh wait right we're the
people right now and then for something
like that though then it could be hey no
we're putting ten dollars a month in so
we're the ones and then as people come
on board and they're willing to put in
the money then they get a say right they
get a say in what does this matter
project was like what does this and so I
don't know he's gonna put me in touch
with the person I don't know what
solution raising works with that and or
together tech but I'm sure there's
something we could put on common when it
first comes out that is so is that the
is that the mystery project that
someone's building in game B or is that
outside of
it's the Dow stack and he's got but
Jordan put me in touch with him all
right
have we heard any more about the mystery
solution and gave me that keeps popping
up but no one will tell us about know
did you see that first oh I mean no one
caught a mystery but you know there was
like we someone posted hey so we need
you know an area to do this you know get
together do scheduling for projects I
think was the one it was and we're like
oh we're doing this one and then someone
goes oh well there's someone building
this that's in game B and I'm like are
they gonna tell anyone yes I just worry
if I just can tell that or something
else yeah no no it's it's not in game B
it's specifically it's someone with it
well that's interesting yeah yeah yeah
yeah that Dow stuff is all that flavors
is kind of what other techniques so
that's good
but time gets into the difference
between hollow chain and Dow stock at
the beginning when I asked him and he
seemed to seem think it was very
concrete I have no way understand it did
you watch it Shiloh did you don't
understand it either the difference in
Apollo chickens out stock after watching
it I feel like I do and I don't think he
described it very well oh okay fair
enough fair enough
I was like it was describing it over my
head anyway I was like well they're I
don't even know how it like it was like
he would couldn't even explain the
difference because they were so
different it's how I was getting what he
was saying it was like in my head down
the same there like an umbrella project
of projects once blockchain and once not
and it's like and they're both very
techy and I don't care whatever so but
I'm excited by the comment that it's
going to exist and that we can use head
anything that's decentralized and helps
us work together more effectively which
is what the data stack is concentrating
on is more of kind of what we're doing
but behind the scenes not live on
YouTube and actually doing it like
actually making the things which you
both are how many conversations which is
a thing you know it sounds interesting
I wouldn't use like it for any of the
main projects now because I'd want to
see you know what it does and how it
works and how it actually behaves but
super cool
idea I would absolutely use it for a
solution raising like what's the worst
they take over the education project and
make it and it's exactly yeah I guess my
point is I would use it for any like
projects that are established and taking
over wiki election but I'm like no I
probably wouldn't for solution reason
itself but for a solution Rosie
yes well yeah if it starts there and
evolves there then do whatever you want
with it yeah I need to dig a little
deeper because reason score would be a
potential tool within you know it's a
governance tool it's one of the you know
it's not a solve all solution but
there's one small piece excited that I
get to come in contact with these
projects even if I can't keep them
straight in my head these amazing things
they could in what exists put so much
easier could be your guys's projects
somewhat separated cuz I had I know you
guys that I know yeah yeah you get to
hear about them in bits over time so it
just keeps reinforcing it yes even then
I wouldn't want to like explain it like
I was trying to get Chantal our cousin
in touch with with Susan and it was like
what do I tell her about your project
though like I need I need the words like
I don't the name isn't gonna like cut it
it's like a few treaty law an invitation
to resume call okay that I can do yeah
word part for me please which is
sometimes people's really Jonah I'm like
I can't put it in language right now my
dining to my cousin like I don't talk to
very often yeah sort of anything else
about the Menem project mean that's you
can end it here we could do the thing
that you wanted to do in a different
time Bentley or weekend just continue
see what happens yeah yeah okay so just
yeah so we're not we're not currently
we're working focusing on building the
community as opposed to any particular
tech
because we don't have a big enough need
yet okay it's like growing our Saturdays
right like how do and I think we're
doing really well like people are
showing up consistently it's the same
people and that's great cuz that is kind
of what we want the same people
consistently showing up until there's
too many and then the idea was I think
we were gonna switch to to feeding do at
9:00 a.m. and 2 p.m. and do it on zoom
I'm ok with figuring that artists we go
right when there's too many of us to be
on stream yard some people watching
comments I'm okay not showing up for the
Saturdays I'm okay just facilitating
putting other people up on the screen
and I'm okay going on to zoom I figure
you know figuring it out there and doing
that but I think it's it's growing and
it's like considering we only have like
80 not 99 89 somewhere members for the
projects and all of the game be
subgroups are like that they actually
have a lot of for the number they have
they have to have a lot of interaction
it's just Facebook doesn't really help
you with your algorithm when you're got
so few people like it's more than there
is in solution raising as there should
be and the wiki gave me wiki looks like
it's got some more activity on there too
so if they do something we may want to
talk to them about integrating the neck
results into it or something yeah let's
make the clear of where the figure out
what should live where yeah oh and on
the project site I added a role I guess
I was working on
so do you mean you added a project poll
on the the knack site
yeah it's trying to figure out what I
need to kind of fill out to support yeah
and by all me if there's any fields that
you need to be able to properly
articulate that let me know that's still
very early days but well I can't think
of anything to put in events I mean we
have all these meetings that we're doing
but for like what for a reason score I'm
not gonna have reason school there might
not be right if you don't do like any
weekly or bi-weekly events under the
umbrella breeze and score it's totally
fun to have that be empty but right like
it if do blue fill it and and wiki
election fill up the the events list and
then we're poor collection reason score
fill up to help needed that at least
helps show like okay here's what it
looks like with multiple projects not
everyone has to do everything cool so
that's that's still good and that's for
both sides that's the like roles that
you already have and then roles that you
need you need help with both cons are
probably good that was one of the
questions I just added the idea cafe as
well like what outside role would have
the most impact if they really come on
right like I need a longer advertise or
whatever that I can't even articulate
that particular diverge another question
I have but it's something like kind of
what are the categories of help that we
think both that we need and that we
think other projects might need right
because it's like I just got a really
vague thing for like marketing you're
like yeah but that could be a hundred
two different roles how how do we want
to categorize it which is true for like
how do we want to categorize people that
have projects that we need that we need
help with but kind of more importantly
how do we think volunteers are gonna be
looking at the lists and wanting it
categorized for sort of what they can do
and how they can help so they can just
zero down and that I can do these things
show me what what I can help with so the
way I've been thinking about doing that
is is not as opposed to having roles and
stuff like that it's really well I mean
or a role would be
in my mind either a skill set that's
needed for a thing or a or an actual
task that you do so you're responsible
for doing X so I would almost want it to
be a just a group of tags that I put on
so I might label it like community
manager but that doesn't mean anything
like even software device it doesn't
mean anything so it really needs to be a
lot more specific like for software
developer you'd list the actual tech you
wouldn't say software developer you know
what I mean right
okay because are you talking about kind
of like a long text area look like just
where where you could almost like at
least to start with have like a bulleted
list appears the five to ten things that
this role would need to do actual you
know for a marketing person you know put
like post on social media once a week
and you know find out articles and try
to establish a relationship like those
sort of actual things they go under the
umbrella of the bigger like how you find
it group yeah it would be nice though if
they were actual tags and then you could
search by tags I don't know if neck
openness and tagging I think I think she
means so like if somebody thought that
for example they can code in a certain
teams you know in a certain language you
might have a tag that says not just
coder but a coder like in c-sharp or in
whatever and then I can look for coding
in C sharp
oh there's two projects that help with
that cool I can do that yeah like if
you're a you know if if I'm running a
team of people there might be there
might be some tasks that we trade back
and forth and it's nicer if if you know
that your job role is is these 50 roles
which are kind of tasks and skill set
right and responsibility it's really
like responsibilities what are the
individual responsibilities that make
right that that person takes on but
really I don't think of it as a role
like like would traditionally say
software developer manager it's like I'm
the manager that does these 50 things
right and then you can move the role
from person to person
you know as I got it from so it's more
about the individual things they're
doing to try and get as possible which I
totally agree with you not sure how we
do that in act just yet so that might be
a future thing but I totally agree that
that would be awesome to get sort of as
detailed as possible
and I think you probably still need some
kind of a higher level categorization
just to be able to help people drill
down yeah like to maybe start with
developer and then it further breaks
down and a further you know gets even
more specialized into like what
languages and environments and yeah it'd
be nice if it had a yeah hierarchy what
do they call that nomenclature our mom
would like I mean terms would TP
but yeah so yeah that would be that
would be helpful but I don't know if doc
has that feature it's very few systems
that do I mean yeah well this is the
meta project group so this is I guess
the board meeting for what we're calling
together text which is the meta object
ribbon and then we access the two things
I just added to the agenda or what do we
want the question to be next week we
brainstorm some what do we want to
actually talk about next week and I can
post it and then the other question I
had was um oh I'm like I'm a kid no I'm
happy
let me just go back to the agenda
I don't jog my memory or means oh yes
for these board meetings
oh please Mahlon for these board
meetings do we want to post the link for
outside people to come and participate
or just like idea cafes clearly but the
board meeting itself I am just gonna
post it in the game be space right
project indie projects I say yes cuz the
worst happens someone shows up and they
don't know what's going on and that's
cool we let them know what's going on um
but how does everyone else feel about
hosting I say yes until it becomes a
problem is also just how stream guard
works if we have to add them to the
stream so if someone shows up and we add
them in they're a jerk we can kick them
in even if they keep showing up we just
don't have them to the string for
example so yeah on the on the next site
the project rolls yeah it's just uh it's
just a text box right so even just
adding a text area description would
probably be sufficient oh okay yeah I
can do that I think there is uh I forget
what I call that I call this something
bigger it was like I think expected full
or expected
responsibilities order something like
that which i think is on the way up but
it's not like an ad yeah right now it's
not okay
project work type status remember role
name okay off to go add that yeah this
there's something there or turning up on
my screen
could be a british mission probably yeah
I think I probably didn't add up to play
out so I'll have to go as that because
makes its that you'd want that okay I
don't know why Raymond's that's a
different link that's the link for
tomorrow's I think so you're ahead of
the game probably for tomorrow's but let
me just find you on here and also Anjali
[Music]
as well sorry I went into tomorrow's
meeting as well okay I must have I must
have game the wrong one Jamie I'm so why
didn't even come off and then go it's
like if you're in Facebook I think that
link is at the top of the Facebook chain
in the one that you're commenting on in
a minute no key scene that I I posted
the wrong one guys posted tomorrow's for
today clearly I'm on great here you
posted the right one in the the
messaging system so that's why we got it
yeah I'm looking at the room that we're
in and the first comment on the string
it's the same one so I think it's it's
book let's go to Facebook and their link
like yeah there's a new link every week
so if we're trying each individual
session there's a different like a
different links you used to be able to
join on video and audio and that's the
way stream yard works that's not yep we
didn't choose that right and we're using
extreme yarda stream so it's an open
meeting alright oh no no no no stop stop
what's happening go with it by the way
oh yeah chimp waited to mute herself or
going through things and other tabs
alright I went all the way there and it
just literally took we've acted like
could have just posted it right here and
it would have been just fine
that was way too much run around for
that same thing Raymond can you find it
I posted it there hopefully posted under
it
yeah and it won't let me ascend you just
the one personally so there we go it's
there were only have like ten more
minutes anyway
the link will genuinely be under that
post so further on the post in facebook
though usually the first comment
well I in this case it just said it's
just the link itself sometimes it will
preface with like for those who want to
join yeah and also I just said earlier
in this that every Sunday I'm gonna put
out all my links so there it will be
posted in the project the tooth for
Fridays and Saturdays will be posted on
Sundays for the following week so it
should oppose see them Friday morning
for Friday and Saturday though we posted
Sunday and if you want to use the knack
prototype it'll be a bit easier to find
a link there because notice always be in
the write more column yeah that do you
I'm also doing that on Sundays and so
with this question I just want to make
sure it's clear that what Raymond did
first off would have normally worked we
just had a a link issue so what you did
will be fine in the future the same
thing happens and I posted the wrong
link
23 yards one I even double-check and it
somehow yep there was another there was
another game be meeting and I tried two
or three times and they said oh yeah we
had it we were just we went off to other
rooms and I'm like yeah I know I saw
that it's like oh yeah maybe save the
main room for part of it know a few
minutes late anyway which is yeah heavy
moe CEO and come in 10-15 minutes late I
had two things I wanted to go to that
yesterday and then I had this co-op
thing about to go get my dad's
medication which
Lower East End in Vancouver is quite
interesting right now it's not the top
not the topic but property in cope 819
genomeics yeah awesome yeah tomorrow's
is the round table so tomorrow is for
your project and then we just introduced
what we're doing and what we need help
with and then chat for an hour that's
pretty pretty good and Raymond's saying
the game be group but just to be clear
it's the gave me projects great to find
it yes right cuz that's where he's at
right now but just kisses confusion like
having sometimes me posting game be as
well but very rarely it's mainly getting
beat I don't want to spam them or spam
them with come join me for checks I
don't take us out I want to be in minis
they can make actually totally I can fix
myself
we haven't been posting a lot so it's
not no no there's other people who post
way more and way less relevant
everything we do is relevant like it's
it's the issue is you have fighting yeah
and then of course everyone's able to
give feedback on how together we can
move forward with together tech and a
better project like if someone else has
an amazing idea on how to come together
with our projects
everyone's welcome to share we're just
doing that at the moment because other
people weren't we took on projects yeah
okay well I think we're getting close to
the end of the hour unless any other one
of the other things it was just when we
were talking about paying yonas maybe
this isn't the same for everyone else
but there's a difference to me between
us deciding what to make and then
someone going out and making it versus
somebody just making it because they
could write like someone made the
schedule or he made that and it's
awesome I like donuts this thing or the
other one and then you don't make the
knack thing right like there's a
difference between we need it to be X
and then paying someone to make X versus
oh I could do Y so I'm just gonna do why
there's like it happens in the community
that I'm part of quite frequently we're
like so be like
all these garden boxes they took me ten
hours yes but nobody wanted you I'm not
saying this is Yanis but nobody wanted
you to make that right so no that
doesn't count that's not your evening
meal right that's not the same as a
saint
the playroom needs to be clean and
someone organizing it even though under
that other run briella things get done
that are helpful if like it's like you
don't really get credit my boy dork has
to read commissioned and agreed that's
gonna be paid ahead of time to like hey
this is a clean posting we're willing to
pay for this thing you could do anything
you want only this thing pays like you
know so I built Mac no one asked me to I
just went and did it that shouldn't get
paid if suddenly there's a huge push and
there's a bunch of work and stuff like
that then it might become okay to make
these changes that's paid then go ahead
but until the other side yeah
and if we end up using it then a lot
then we could choose to pay server costs
and stuff like that and then and then
you know if we do need more features
than it could be like well I could
volunteer that or I can pay or other
ones and it should all be open source so
if something happens to you we can all
jump in and someone else can add
features right I guess yeah
theoretically we can also if we wanted
like just features done like that but we
didn't want to have a central thing we
could still just put it up on what's
called bounty source for our feature and
that you know whoever wants to do it can
do it and then everyone can go and
contribute to bounty source for it so we
do have options and I think somebody
said in previous meetings like I would
imagine especially for for more things
right now we would start off sort of
long thing slash expecting a volunteers
because we don't have any money right
now and then that's sort of you know
until we say otherwise all the work is
just assuming to be volunteer once we
can actually start offering bounties or
commissions or whatever then we'll wall
me that clear hey this one area is where
you go to see that only the things that
are listed only how they're listed
that's how you get paid like I said this
difference in commissioning it there is
I think a certain amount like there
might be something that someone
able to do right we have time right now
they have the skill they can make it and
we could even commission I didn't get
stayed in the future right like hey this
is valuable if we had $10,000 would love
to pay you $10,000 but we don't so how
about 20,000 in the future right which
is what is the future mean well when we
not our first 20,000 right when we get
200,000 you get to your 20,000 or
whatever that looks like that it can be
an actual commission but also because I
don't think anyone's gonna volunteer to
volunteer its gonna volunteer to get
paid in the future when they don't trust
the project right when they don't think
that that's gonna happen so it's partly
your volunteer you because you might
never see this but also we're paying you
double we're paying you like what it's
worth because we understand there's risk
involved and not getting mattered you
know those those kind of things that
doesn't mean it's only because we don't
have money so we're not gonna pay you
but future lis we will probably have
money and what you're doing is worth is
worth it but I would love to first look
for volunteers right together Tech's
bottom line how we help compete the
current tech is that a lot of people
have ingenuity in the ability to
volunteer and do that and the skill and
then when we don't have that we pay oh
yeah
all right I don't have any closing
comments before we say goodbye till
tomorrow Fridays is always weird can see
each other the next day but maybe it's
not a good time no five minutes that's a
question I've been trying to just absorb
whatever I can and I guess I'm just a
little bit confused together Tech and
the med project what is the meta project
for together tech is there that still
just open-ended right now is it
something that we all could collaborate
on one meta project or is that not so
together tech theoretically is the meta
project the idea being that the other
tech is the tech cooperative that we all
we all own together and operate together
what does that look like well in my
vision a year ago it looks like the
users owning it and that's coming
together and figuring out what most
empowers our lives we got involved in
game B
then ever people actually got involved
it turns out everyone has a project
everyone has their baby and so it made
more sense to find out how can we create
omnimon solutions for our projects
instead of just for the people and so
now we're focusing on what does it look
like to be part of solution raising part
of we collection part of reason score
and how can we facilitate our common
problems together right everyone gotta
figure out marketing and everyone has to
figure out funding and trust how do we
do that well we're my kids calling me
from the other room well I'm - camera Oh
how do we facilitate the undoing
solutions and so that's the matter
project it's name together tech it might
you know the end of game B takes it over
I change the name but the idea is that
does that make more more sense we
interchange that a project and together
tag it yeah it isn't a specific thing it
is the umbrella of how do we create Omni
win solutions together within our
current capacity financially skill wise
all of that that's currently like the
nack project list and the scheduling and
all of these things that were kind of
done under the ability to gather tech of
hey yes there's a need for that and
someone went out and made it
they just weren't Commission like that
does that make sense I love it yeah kind
of like it started out we just called it
the meta project but before it really
was anything and then then jublee
already had a project called together
tech that we're like you know I should
steal that name and then it's called
game B projects and Facebook because
it's sort of a part of the game B
community like even if you look in the
URL it's actually got together techie in
the URL so like all three of them are
kind of the same thing that I've evolved
to be that I was trying to like just for
myself figure out like what is together
tech like how would I describe it to
someone and the list that I had was like
it's kind of one of its main purposes is
to come up with those best practices for
Omni one projects and it might you know
it might not be suitable for all of them
it might be like here's what tech looks
like here's what like if you're doing
farming as a part of an omni moon
project here's what we've learned
I think it'll end up being like a
network of Omni wind projects
and then it's meant to itself act like
an omni wind project so we can sort of
test out some of the tools and the
strategies that were we're talking about
that that's what it is to me I know that
helps so Steve had a good question what
does it look like to be part of KB
together the tech meditech so yeah
together the tech medtech are pretty
much the same bet meta meta project and
together the tech are pretty much the
same thing I mean yeah so we're
practicing game B by building technology
together
that's a meta project because the
project is to help other projects do it
so better project is what it is the name
is together TAC and all this fluctuates
because we don't know what we're doing
but yeah participation in in together
tech and and the meta project is just
coming to this meeting saying what we
want to do together and figuring out how
to do it
so you are all here by participants like
do you want to be in it you're in it
attendee I don't want to be in it
and that's it and then we build it
together I mean so you know we were
starting to do some stuff but then we
kind of thought well we need more people
because we're just kind of like building
castles in the sky so whatever y'all
wants to do together to make the world a
better place a little bit through
technology just show up and tell us what
you want figure it out together is that
right yeah I think between the three of
us that's a pretty rural there's a yes
that those three enemies all right is
now the our I think we should as my kid
doesn't call a fourth time I'm going
deal with that so should we say goodbye
to YouTube or was there anything all
right thanks guys for watching and we'll
be your here tomorrow at 9 a.m.
come and join bring your project what's
great solutions together that's nice
Pacific yes they